A Guide to the King George County (Va.) Records, 1765-1970 circa
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
King George County (Va.) Records, 1765-1970 circa
Library of Virginia
1059306-1174959 circa
21 boxes and 3 volumes
King George County (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from King George County (Va.) under accession numbers 41899, 41903, 41904, 42662 42759, and 42999.
Biographical Information
King George County was named of in honor of King George I. The county was formed from Richmond County by a statute of 23 December 1720. The county court first met on 19 May 1721. The county seat is King George.
Most loose records prior to 1830 are missing. Volumes that record deeds, court orders, and wills exist.
Scope and Content
King George County (Va.) Records, 1765-1970 circa, includes miscellaneous records from the following series: Court Records; Overseers of the Poor Records; Fiduciary Records, Bonds, Commissions, Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records; Military and Pension Records; Road and Bridge Records; Organization Records; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics; Public Buildings and Grounds Records; Land Records; Health and Medical Records; Miscellaneous Records; and Board of Supervisors Records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional King George County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
See the Lost Records Localities Digital Collection available at Virginia Memory.
For more information and a listing of lost records localities see Lost Records research note.
Contents List
- Court Records, Overseers of the Poor Records, 1850-1900
- Fiduciary Records; Court Records, 1800-1900:
  Fiduciary Records: Inventories, accounts, etc., 1875-1895; Miscellaneous Court Papers (judgments, criminal, etc.)
- Fiduciary Records; Court Records 1860-1919:
  Fiduciary Records: Fiduciary Accounts, 1910-1919; Inventories, Appraisements, etc., 1874-1899; Inventories of sales, etc., 1864-1874; Court Records: Miscellaneous Court Papers (judgments, criminal, etc.)
- Fiduciary Records and Court Bonds, 1850-1900
- Court Records, 1845-1900:
  commonwealth causes, criminal papers, jury records, etc.
- Court Records; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1850-1900
- Court Records, Election Records, and Fiduciary Records, 1860-1900
- Records, 1866-1918:
  Court Records: common law papers, judgments, criminal, 1866-1910; Military and Pension Records: List of men who entered military service from King George County in World War I, 1917-1918, Roster of Confederate Pensioners in Virginia, 1917; Road and Bridge Records, 1890; Board of Supervisors Records, 1878.
- Records, 1845-1891:
  Military and Pension Records: Civil War pension applications, 1887; Overseers of Poor: Overseer of Poor reports and appointments, etc., insolvent lists 1854-1891; Tax and Fiscal Records: claims for slaves who escaped during the late war, 1861-1865, petition to exempt certain negroes from taxes, 1868, patrol claims and commissions, 1855-1861, liquor licenses, 1868-1870; Court Records: Judgments, 1826-1855, Criminal: Commonwealth Causes, 1845-1855; Organization Records: Free Union Society of King George County, 1887.
- Marriage Records and Vital Statistics; Fiduciary Records, 1871-1909:
  Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Lists of births, 1871-1890; Fiduciary Records: Fiduciary Accounts, 1874-1909.
- Records, 1830-1900:
  Road and Bridge Records: Road Work Claims; Tax and Fiscal Records: Crow Scalp Claims, Fox Scalp Claims, Salt Receipts, Sheep Killed Claims, Land Assessments; Court Records; Public Buildings and Grounds Records: Jail Related Papers; Election Records.
- Estrays, Hawkers and Peddlers Licenses; Records of Land Causes, 1792-1846:
  Tax and Fiscal Records: Estrays, Hawkers and Peddlers Licenses, 1792-1846; Court Records: Records of Land Causes, 1793-1813.
- Records, 1698-1723
  Court Records; Land Records; Fiduciary Records; Election Records; Bonds,Commissions,Oaths.
- Records, 1830-1900 circa:
  Court Records, Fiduciary Records, Lunacy Papers and Tax and Fiscal Records.
- Records, 1861-1880, undated:
  Road and Bridge Records, 1876, 1880, undated; Land Records: Maps and Plats, 1871,undated; Tax and Fiscal Records: Lists of Licenses, Lists of Merchants, Delinquent Tax Lists, 1860-1871; Overseer of the Poor reports, 1861, 1868-1870.
- Surveyors of Roads; Board of Health Records, 1892-1937:
  Road and Bridge Records: Surveyors of Roads, 1892-1895; Board of Health records, 1923-1937.
- Miscellaneous Bonds, 1765-1789:
  Officials' Bonds, guardian bonds, administrator bonds, inspector bonds, ferry bonds, ordinary bonds, etc., 1765-1789.
- Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records; Miscellaneous Records, 1870s-1918 circa:
- Tax and Fiscal Records; Bonds,Oaths,Commissions, 1800s-1930s circa:
  Tax and Fiscal Records: merchants licenses and miscellaneous; Bonds,Oaths,Commissions: oaths of office, 1800s-1930s circa.
- Board of Supervisors Records; Miscellaneous Records, 1920-1940 circa:
  Board of Supervisors Records: Papers done with, 1920-1922; Miscellaneous Records: Applications for enrollment in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), 1930s ca.; Surplus Commodity Distribution Project (WPA), 1930s circa.
- Court Records; Board of Supervisors Records; Fiduciary Records, 1900-1949 circa:
  Court Records: Common Law Papers done with, 1911-1915 and Common Law Papers, etc., 1900-1940s; Board of Supervisors Records: Old papers pending before the board, 1900-1922 circa; Board of Supervisors papers, undated; Fiduciary Records: Fiduciary accounts filed, 1900-1940s circa.
- Court Records; Election Records, 1844-1970:
  Court Records: Actions at Law, 1948-1949; Election Records: Report of Registrars of Persons Registered, 1936-1970; Court Records: Executions Returned, 1844-1880.
- Bonds,Commissions,Oaths; Election Records, 1893-1981:
  Bonds,Commissions,Oaths: Bonds of Officers and Others: 1893-1937; Election Records: Abstracts of Elections: 1961-1981.
- Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records, 1881-1948:
  Election Records: Abstracts of Elections, 1881-1948; Tax and Fiscal Records: Capitation Tax Lists, 1910-1941.